KIIBATI OLUWATOBI ADEOJO

WINNIPEG, MANITOBA, CANADA

Mobile: 204-881-7664, Email: kiibatitoo@gmail.com, Website: https://kiibati-portfolio.firebaseapp.com/

SUMMARY

I am a Full Stack Developer, with over 4 years experience across the Health Care and App Development Startup industry. He has assisted companies and clients with web applications, web backends, mobile app developments and UI/UX designs, with deep expertise in Cross Platform Mobile App Development, Web App Development and Backend Technologies.

EDUCATION

University of Manitoba Bachelor of Computer Science (B.Sc.)

(Graduated February 2020)

Area of Concentration: Human-Computer Interaction and Graphics.

SKILLS

Technical

- Created algorithms and designed applications using C, C++, Java, Python, Dart and C#.
- Good experience in computer graphics using Unreal Engine, Three.js, OpenGL and Processing.
- Designed several websites with HTML, CSS, Tailwind CSS, SASS, Bootstrap, JavaScript and jQuery.
- Developed strong 3D maths and Computer Graphics math.
- Developed applications with object-oriented programming, test driven development, multithreading and performance optimization techniques.
- Applied refactoring techniques, strong debugger knowledge and strong programming practices.
- Learned new software's, paradigms and programming languages fast to apply to projects.

ADDITIONAL SKILLS

- Programming Languages: Q, SQL, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Ruby, Python, Tailwind CSS, React JS, Elixir, Shell Script, etc.
- **Tools**: GitHub, Git-Bash, GitLab, SourceTree, Elasticsearch, Algolia, Firebase, Slack, Android Studio, Google Cloud Functions, Google Cloud Platforms, Kdb+, TensorFlow.
- **Software's**: Blender, Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign and Microsoft Office Suite (Word, Excel, PowerPoint & Outlook).
- Others: JavaFX, XML, JSON, GraphQL, WebSocket, JWT and Markdown.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Developer | mmHg Inc.

April. 2020 - Present

- Working on multiple health sector projects at the same time and delivering amazing design.
- Internalization of mobile apps to make them accessible to different people in different languages.
- Optimizing old code to work with the new SDK and to deliver faster response times.
- Developed apps with Flutter for front end and Java Spring for backend.

Full Stack Developer | Ommaty Technologies

Nov. 2020 - April 2020

- Creating a full backend with Node.js, Express, Firebase and MariaDB.
- Using GitHub Actions CI and Git version control to ensure code maintainability.
- Node.js, Maria DB, Next.js were used to create a neat and reusable backend REST API.
- Backend and frontend optimization to make the app production ready.

Applying test driven development in creating the Flutter front end.

Web Developer | Vancouver Brain Injury Association

June. 2020 - September 2020

- Developed an entire WordPress website and theme from scratch using PHP, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap and other web frameworks.
- Completely changed the website from about 9 seconds load time to milliseconds load times with better UI.
- Worked extensively with customising a fast theme in the WordPress CMS.
- Wrote a detailed technical documentation on how to update the website for non-programmers.
- Applied donor-centric languages to draw more donors to the cause.
- Managed several websites and domains.

Mobile Application Development | FIVERR

September 2020 - Present

- Developing a mobile application with Flutter, Dart and Firebase.
- Designed mobile application UI and implemented the functionality.
- Listened and implemented customers ideas into a mobile application.
- Troubleshot and debugged several applications.

Cable Tech Support for Rogers | Sykes Enterprise

January 2018 to May 2018

Red River Exhibition Park, SALESPERSON/CUSTOMER SERVICE REPRESENTATIVE – June 2017 University of Manitoba, COMPUTER SCIENCE TUTOR – VOLUNTEER Immanuel Fellowship Church, AUDIO/VISUAL OPERATOR - 2014 - Present – VOLUNTEER

RELATED PROJECTS

WEBAPPS and WEBSITES

- Successfully developed a contract website and personal portfolio with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, iOuerv.
- Created and hosted a commercial store website for Bivic Foods from scratch.
 (www.bivicfoods.com)
- Implemented a blogging website from scratch by creating an entire WordPress theme from scratch. (www.vbia.ca)
- Used NPM as a package manager to manage several JavaScript frameworks.
 (www.aworanapp.com)
- Developed a server-side distributed ring system like torrents using python and other web languages.

12 ASSISTANT, QUIZMASTER, VALOFRAG, AWORAN - 2017 till present

- Google play store app with 4-star rating developed with Android Studio.
- Applied fast image and list loading techniques with excellent object-oriented programming.
- Applied the Agile, Scrum principles and used Git Version Control.
- Worked with a group and implemented the 3-Tier Architecture for building this software.
- Test driven development including Unit, Integration and System Tests.
- Developing a social media app with Flutter, Dart and Firebase. [Current] (www.aworanapp.com).

IMAGE PROCESSING and WEBSCRAPING PROJECTS

- Researched and implemented PPM and PGM image formatters using Python.
- Developed several programs for image manipulation and working with external packages.
- Developed "indeed.ca" that scrapes all jobs from the website and other web scraping projects.